e-flux.com 2019-03-31

# Data privacy policy - e-flux

e-flux takes the protection of your personal data very seriously and strictly adheres to the applicable data protection laws, in particular to the provisions of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation) (hereinafter referred to as “GDPR”). 

Our digital services may contain links to other websites of third party service providers to which this data protection declaration does not apply.

## 1\. Responsible authority

Responsible for the processing of your personal data is

e-flux  
311 East Broadway  
New York, NY 10002, USA

If you have any questions regarding data protection, please contact us at the above-mentioned postal address, with the addition “data protection” or at the e-mail address dataprivacy [​at​] e-flux.com.

## 2\. Purposes of the processing of personal data

The use of our website is usually possible without providing personal data. Personal data, such as names, addresses or e-mail addresses are always provided on a voluntary basis if possible. These data will not be passed on to third parties without your express consent, with the exception of the service providers named below, who support us in providing our services.

**2.1. Communication data**

We process your communication data (name, e-mail address) in order to be able to contact you. Personal data that you provide to us by e-mail and/or via the contact form on this website will only be processed for correspondence with you or only for the purpose for which you have made the data available to us. 

The basis for this data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR, which permits the processing of data for the fulfilment of a contract or pre-contractual measures.

**2.2. Newsletter/ e-flux announcements**

e-flux operates newsletters on arts and architecture (hereinafter referred to as “e-flux announcements”), which are direct e-mailings of text and image press releases, sent several times a day. With your consent you can subscribe to e-flux announcements. The main topics of the respective e-flux announcement are specified in the declaration of consent. If you would like to subscribe to e-flux announcements, we require an e-mail address from you as well as information that allows us to verify that you are the owner of the e-mail address provided and that you agree to receive the respective e-flux announcement. For this purpose, we will send you an e-mail to the specified e-mail address with a confirmation link (double-opt-in). If you do not confirm your registration within [72 hours], your information will be automatically deleted after one month. 

The only mandatory information for subscribing to e-flux announcements is your e-mail address. The indication of further, separately marked data is voluntary and is used to be able to address you personally. In addition, we store your IP addresses and the time of registration and confirmation. The purpose of this procedure is to be able to prove your registration and, if necessary, to clarify a possible misuse of your personal data. We do not collect any further data in this context. We use this data exclusively for sending the requested e-flux announcement. If we use a processor to send the e-flux announcements, we will of course comply with the applicable data protection laws.

You can revoke your consent to receive e-flux announcements and unsubscribe at any time. You can cancel the subscription by clicking on the link provided in every e-flux announcement, by e-mail to[Newsletter@e-flux.com] or by sending a message to the contact data specified under section 1 (e.g. e-mail, fax, letter).

The data will be processed on the basis of your consent pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. You can revoke your consent at any time. The lawfulness of the data processing processes already carried out remains unaffected by the revocation.

**2.3. Google Analytics**

Our website uses Google Analytics, a website analysis service by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies", text files that are stored on your computer to analyse your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually sent to and stored at a Google server in the U.S.A.

You find more information concerning the treatment of user data by Google Analytics in [Google's Privacy Policy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245).

You may prevent the installation of cookies by adjusting the settings of your browser; however, if you do so, you may be unable to use all features of this website. Further, you may prevent the collection of data generated by cookies (including your IP address) and related to the use of this websites as well as the processing of such data by Google by downloading and installing the plug-in under the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

You can also prevent collection by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie is set to prevent future collection of your data when you visit this website: [insert a link using the code here]

For more information on terms of use and data protection, please visit <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/> or <https://policies.google.com/>. Please note that the code "anonymizeIp" has been added to Google Analytics on this website to ensure anonymous collection of IP addresses (so-called IP masking).

Google Analytics is used and Google cookies are stored and evaluated for statistical purposes on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. We have a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize our services.

**2.4. Pingdom**

Our website uses Pingdom, a service of Pingdom AB, Kopparbergsvägen 8, 72213 Västeras, Sweden. Pingdom uses, among other things, cookies which are stored on your computer and which enable an analysis of the use of the website. During use, data, in particular the shortened IP address and activities of users, may be transmitted to a server of Pingdom AB and stored there. 

You may prevent the installation of cookies by adjusting the settings of your browser; however, if you do so, you may be unable to use all features of this website.

You can prevent the collection and forwarding of personal data (in particular your shortened IP address) and the processing of this data by deactivating the execution of Java-Script in your browser or by installing a tool such as "NoScript". 

Further information on data protection when using Pingdom can be found under the following link: <https://www.pingdom.com/legal/privacy-policy>.

We use Pingdom for statistical purposes on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR. We have a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize our services.

**2.5. Data processing for the fulfilment of legal obligations**

In addition, we may process your data to fulfil legal obligations (e.g. regulatory requirements, commercial and tax storage and proof obligations).

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c GDPR, which permits processing for the fulfilment of a legal obligation.

**2.6. Log files**

Whenever our websites are accessed, usage data is transmitted through the respective Internet browser and stored in log files, the so-called server log files. The data records stored in this way contain the following data: Date and time of access, name of the page accessed, shortened IP address, referrer URL (originating URL from which you accessed the website), the amount of data transferred, as well as product and version information of the browser used. The shortened IP addresses of the visitors are deleted or made anonymous after the end of use.

The basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR, which permits the processing of data to protect the legitimate interests of the data controller, provided that the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject do not prevail.

## 3\. Data security

Your personal data is transmitted encrypted. This applies to your communication data if you use our contact form and when registering for e-flux announcements. We use the SSL (Secure Socket Layer) coding system. Furthermore, we protect our websites and other systems through technical and organizational measures against loss, destruction, access, modification or distribution of your data by unauthorized persons.

## 4\. Categories of receipt of personal data

Insofar as we make use of the services of third parties to carry out our services, we process personal data according to the provisions of the GDPR. Service providers who support us in providing our services to you are the it-service providers, hosting providers and e-mail service providers.

## 5\. Duration of data storage

In principle, we delete your data as soon as it is no longer required for the above-mentioned purposes, unless temporary storage is still necessary. Thus we store your data on the basis of legal proof and storage obligations. In addition, we keep your data for the period during which claims can be asserted against our company (statutory limitation period of three or up to thirty years).

## 6\. Rights of the persons concerned

You can request information about your personal data stored by us and under certain conditions request the correction or deletion of your data by contacting us via our contact data given under section 1. You may also have the right to restrict the processing of your data and to have the data you provide disclosed in a structured, common and machine-readable format. If you have given us your consent to process personal data for specific purposes, you can revoke your consent at any time with effect for the future. You may object to the processing of your data for direct marketing purposes. If we process your data to protect legitimate interests, you may object to such processing for reasons arising from your particular situation. You can also contact a data protection supervisory authority. If you have any questions regarding data protection, please contact us at dataprivacy [​at​] e-flux.com.
